Tyler Schumacher

Middleport, NY 14105 tyschumacher@proton.me **WWW:** https://tylerschumacher.dev **WWW:** https://github.com/traweezy

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a full stack web developer, with over 9 years of experience. Currently working in the sports betting industry, while previously working with large financial banks and fintech companies creating both public facing web application and internal tooling

WORK HISTORY

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER | 12/2021 to Current Caesars Sportsbook - Jersey City, NJ

- Create and maintain back office trading platforms for traders to trade before and during events using technologies such as react and typescript.
- Optimize applications to handle large amounts of live data, while allowing the end users to navigate and interact with the applications in an intuitive way.
- Lead team in scrum ceremonies, i.e stand up, retro, team demos, etc.
- Work with designers and end users to ensure users are having the best possible user experience, by using tools like Fullstory and responding to user feedback and interviews.

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER | 12/2017 to 12/2021 Instinct - New York, NY

- Owned and maintained node applications that exposed a REST API, Graphql API, and websockets to back company's internal and client facing web applications. Built with Express, Typescript, and MySQL.
- Designed and contributed to front end application for clients and internal tooling, built with React.
- Redesigned and reimplemented multiple flash based applications to modern React applications.
- Maintained web applications team's DevOps needs, such as Gitlab CI maintenance, logging and error handling through kubernetes, etc.

FRONT END DEVELOPER (CONSULTANT) | 06/2017 to 12/2017 Lab49 - New York, NY

- Consulting for the world's leading investment banks, asset managers, and exchanges to design, build and maintain advanced solutions.
- Building frontend software using the technologies such as React, Redux, SCSS while working with Java based back ends.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER | 10/2015 to 06/2017 Twisted Rope - Buffalo, NY

- Create web applications for clients using web technologies such as React, Redux, Node.js, and SCSS.
- Build landing pages and ad campaigns while adhering to modern web best practices.

EDUCATION